[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde5", "question": "What morbid structure traditionally has thirteen steps?", "answer": "A gallow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a3", "question": "What is the term for the official record of a dog\u2019s ancestry?", "answer": "Pedigree", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60078be90eee65b76b9f266e", "question": "In which country did the first World War I battle take place?", "answer": "Belgium (The first official battle of WWI occurred at the city named Liege. The city was taken by Germany by August 15, 1914.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5c", "question": "Which of the four biblical Gospels was written by an ex-tax collector?", "answer": "Matthew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f66", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the Sugarcubes?", "answer": "Bjork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa6a173838c5c8a417f30", "question": "How many teeth does an aardvark have?", "answer": "None", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b2", "question": "Which of the Seven Wonders of the World was situated approximately 50 miles south of modern Baghdad?", "answer": "The Hanging Gardens of Babylon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f93efe83fe1f2a824c31", "question": "Who created the first electrically lit Christmas tree?", "answer": "Edward H. Johnson was an American inventor best known for creating the first electrically illuminated Christmas tree in 1882", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b397", "question": "What did American Harland David Sanders give to the world in the 1930s?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fcecfe83fe1f2a824c47", "question": "What skill characterized the \"Homo habilis\" species?", "answer": "Tool-making", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a4f090aac110e416706f", "question": "What fruit are Kriek lambics made with?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339893", "question": "What was Lucy and Ricky's last name on the TV series \"I Love Lucy\"?", "answer": "Ricardo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb737c95e259d786908732c", "question": "Who was the Bolshevik leader that was exiled by Joseph Stalin after Vladimir Lenin\u2019s death?", "answer": "Leon Trotsky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab00", "question": "What stretch of water lies between New Brunswick, Maine and Nova Scotia?", "answer": "Bay of Fundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adba", "question": "What was the first US city to have a subway system?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76d", "question": "What lake in Oregon was created about 7,000 years ago by the eruption of Mount Mazama?", "answer": "Crater Lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be43", "question": "What is known throughout the world as the King of Fruits?", "answer": "Durian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c88e83422f44c2d77a29c46", "question": "Reaching 20,320 feet (6,194 meters) above sea level, Denali is located in what US state?", "answer": " Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339122", "question": "Which famous character did Jean de Brunhoff create the image of?", "answer": "Babar the Elephant", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958f", "question": "What is the name of the genetically modified disease in the movie \"Mission: Impossible II\"?", "answer": "Chimera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b4", "question": "What wise guys are forever linked to the phrase: \"Nyuk, nyuk, nyuk\"?", "answer": "The 3 Stooges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f6", "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed1", "question": "What reality show gave America the catchphrase \"That's hot\"?", "answer": "The Simple Life", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f167a1f7c52aae91cc07bb", "question": "What country borders the Republic of Guinea-Bissau to the north?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a233", "question": "What famous actor was slated to play the alien in the 1987 film \"Predator\" but was replaced?", "answer": "Jean-Claude Van Damme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2b", "question": "Who became an animated Disney megastar after replacing Oswald the Lucky Rabbit?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb7", "question": "In Shakespeare's play who was the wife of Othello?", "answer": "Desdemona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ff9d13a3a814d89068c58", "question": "What unit of measurement is approximately 100 fathoms?", "answer": "A Cable", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb5d285dad637d903c8822", "question": "What is Valentine's Day called in Brazil?", "answer": "Dia dos Namorados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a447", "question": "Which river runs through Paris?", "answer": "Seine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d23", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"National Velvet\"?", "answer": "Horse racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccaecec223966ae8f889c", "question": "How many pounds of food does Hollywood superstar Dwayne \"the Rock\" Johnson consume daily?", "answer": "The Rock is well known to consume 10 pounds of food daily and accordingly travels with a 40,000-pound personal gym set!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5655f33a95c66dc4fe756", "question": "What does a phrenologist measure?", "answer": "Skulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e5ebfe83fe1f2a824bc7", "question": "Which medieval queen was married to both Louis VII of France and Henry II of England?", "answer": "Eleanor of Aquitaine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7dd", "question": "Which Canadian provinces are known as the \"Maritime Provinces\"?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590678ebff9c0647b50a804e", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd38", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd8937e83c707845b2176", "question": "In what State were the exteriors of the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\" filmed?", "answer": "The exteriors of the film took place outside a soon-to-be demolished reformatory in Mansfield, Ohio.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af44", "question": "What war ended at the Battle of San Jacinto?", "answer": "Texas Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d1159a4fea7fe947a22268", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd4f", "question": "The Eisner Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Comic books", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73b", "question": "What psychiatrist developed the principal of \"synchronicity\"?", "answer": "Carl Jung", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8fbce01dd7bf43be5e855", "question": "Who said, \"Imagination is more important than knowledge\"?", "answer": "Albert Einstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071dc23745b36be73039dc", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358d015db0d66a186cb55e", "question": "Lisbon lies on which river?", "answer": "Tagus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4aa", "question": "Which desert covers part of China and Mongolia?", "answer": "Gobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b6b1e662d71a5365100c", "question": "What is the name of the vampire hunter and animator in Laurell K. Hamilton's \"The Harlequin\"?", "answer": "Anita Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398bf", "question": "What actor died at the age of 24 while driving his Porsche Spyder?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5d", "question": "Who was the Roman God of Love?", "answer": "Cupid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fbae8510738315b1fb74e28", "question": "What is the only major city located on two continents?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4e", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Girl in the Kremlin\"?", "answer": "Natalie Darryl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a096", "question": "Which film features the line, \"I could have been a contender\"?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53a", "question": "In what State is it illegal to smoke from a pipe after sunset?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962f", "question": "\"Three's Company\" is an American remake of which British sitcom?", "answer": "Man about the House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339974", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Lenny's real full name?", "answer": "Lenford Leonard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd417bac329055bc655127b", "question": "Where were U.S. coins with the letters \"CC\" on them minted?", "answer": "Carson City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339890", "question": "Which of the Marx brothers had a mustache and smoked cigars?", "answer": "Groucho Marx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c780", "question": "Part of Dr. Eugene Shoemaker's ashes are buried at what unique place?", "answer": "The Moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601219cf63c99d48cd169afb", "question": "What is someone who shoes horses?", "answer": "A farrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49d", "question": "Self-rising flour contains what crucial ingredient?", "answer": "Baking powder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339574", "question": "In, Santa Baby by Madonna what kind of fur does she want him to slip under the tree?", "answer": "A sable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b64a06d333868d34d6f0", "question": "Who first flew an airplane nonstop across the Atlantic?", "answer": "John Alcock and Arthur Brown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbac", "question": "What sport takes place in a velodrome?", "answer": "Track cycling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2132b31a458464a93c44e", "question": "The red food-coloring carmine is extracted from which source?", "answer": "Crushed beetles called cochineal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfc5c9dc5ec6cd98a831b", "question": "Who painted \"The Birth of Venus\"?", "answer": "Sandro Botticelli", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e910215d7247dfc0fa00310", "question": "At what speed do massless particles travel in vacuum?", "answer": "Speed of light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ca", "question": "Who played the male lead in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65723ae7e414034b5aed7", "question": "Where were the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution, and the Bill of Rights stored during World War II?", "answer": "Fort Knox", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d43", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Alien 3\"?", "answer": "Sigourney Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d06341a1c922dd1ac64a9", "question": "Who wrote the 1980 novel \"The Number of the Beast\"?", "answer": "Robert A. Heinlein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5a", "question": "What literary work inspired Franz Ferdinand's \"Love and Destroy\" song?", "answer": "The Master and Margarita", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddc4a6ce05a3942286d9a", "question": "\"A Charlie Brown Christmas\" greatly influenced the sales of what product?", "answer": "Aluminum Christmas Trees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339359", "question": "What does the \"D.J.\" stand for in D.J. Tanner's name in the TV show \"Full House\"?", "answer": "Donna Jo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba78", "question": "How many strings does the typical mandolin have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c332", "question": "What was the purpose of the ancient medicinal confection made from the marshmallow plant?", "answer": "To treat irritated mucous membranes and increase the flow of breast milk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a1e1d67b5a031299b74573a", "question": "The Okapi is native to which country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f0b0ff048f679a45aaa3", "question": "Sociophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Social evaluation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac88", "question": "Which battle saw the final defeat of Napoleon?", "answer": "Waterloo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e65", "question": "What kind of information resource takes its name from a Hawaiian word for \"quick\"?", "answer": "A wiki", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd7", "question": "In episode of \"Seinfeld\", what popular candy did Jerry become addicted to?", "answer": "Pez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af37", "question": "What was completed in 1869 at Promontory, Utah?", "answer": "Transcontinental Railway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b371951c3f17ccc40c8e1f", "question": "Which Irish poet said \"There are no strangers here; Only friends you have not yet met.\"?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a3", "question": "Who was the 1994 Fifa World Cup winner?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd82", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Ebirah?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f81", "question": "Which is the only Shakespeare play with the name of an English town in the title?", "answer": "The Merry Wives of Windsor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5aab2f4258d116dab4aecb48", "question": "What is racing driver's, Jean Alesi, birth name?", "answer": "Giovanni Alesi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f91", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Turning Point\"?", "answer": "Leslie Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d94", "question": "What Jazz Age celebrity published a single novel \"Save Me the Waltz\", before dying in a 1948 fire?", "answer": "Zelda Sayre Fitzgerald", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feb31db7e83c707845b20c2", "question": "What meteorological phenomenon causes a warm current of water to appear every three to seven years in the eastern Pacific Ocean, causing unusual weather conditions all over the world?", "answer": "El Ni\u00f1o", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c636", "question": "Which two features are longer on a hare than a rabbit?", "answer": "Legs and Ears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c929", "question": "What is a bactrian?", "answer": "Two-humped camel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c550", "question": "What word for a part of the eye is also the name of the Greek Goddess of the Rainbow?", "answer": "Iris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c5", "question": "What is the official state animal of the US state of Oregon?", "answer": "The beaver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b6", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Principal Charming\", where does Skinner buy an engagement ring for Patty?", "answer": "The Family Jewels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c635", "question": "Earth's seasonal changes are caused by what?", "answer": "Earth's axial tilt as it orbits the Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddfb96ce05a3942286db1", "question": "What was the first videogame to feature basketball legend Michael Jordan?", "answer": "Jordan vs. Bird: One on One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc100e469bb8041d07a06b", "question": "In 1917 a bakery in Chattanooga, Tennessee introduced what popular Southern treat?", "answer": "MoonPie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea788fff048f679a45abdb", "question": "What is a \"Haricot Vert\"?", "answer": "A tender string bean", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1bd", "question": "What year did Ferdinand Porsche and his team finish the design of the VW Beetle?", "answer": "1938", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c9", "question": "In the military, what does the abbreviation G.I. stand for?", "answer": "Government Issue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea80c8ff048f679a45ac1c", "question": "The Black Death was caused by fleas carried by what animal?", "answer": "Rodents", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b885e662d71a53651025", "question": "Which German painter was sometimes court painter to King Henry VIII of England after 1536?", "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0eb", "question": "Christopher Cockerell is best known for invented what?", "answer": "The hovercraft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e828fe83fe1f2a824bd9", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3c", "question": "During what decade did the Charleston become the dance craze?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e67", "question": "Who solves crimes in Bayport, located in Barmet Bay?", "answer": "The Hardy Boys", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af57", "question": "Which country do you associate with the Easter Rising?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c88", "question": "What Oscar winner for Ed Wood turned down the role of Spock on Star Trek?", "answer": "Martin Landau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a07e", "question": "Who won an Oscar for the soundtrack to \"Chariots of Fire\"?", "answer": "Vangelis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339375", "question": "In the movie \"Cast Away\", how long was Chuck Nolan marooned on the island?", "answer": "4 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad9", "question": "Edmonton is the capital of which Canadian province?", "answer": "Alberta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b0e86c964118b2bb3809c5", "question": "In Slovenia, Saint Valentine is considered the saint of good health and the patron of whom?", "answer": "Beekeepers and pilgrims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fbaea1a0738315b1fb74e2a", "question": "Phlebitis is the inflimation of what?", "answer": "A vein", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba37", "question": "What theme park did Dolly Parton open in Tennessee?", "answer": "Dollywood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa8", "question": "What flavor of schnapps is used to make the drink Fuzzy Navel?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121ac063c99d48cd169b07", "question": "Where was the world\u2019s first speeding ticket issued?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323740bf195a31e15d73c3", "question": "Lisbon lies on which river?", "answer": "Tagus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c7", "question": "What planet was Mork from in the TV show \"Mork & Mindy\"?", "answer": "Ork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede1066ce05a3942286dc0", "question": "What city did Frank Sinatra help immortalize as \"That Toddlin' Town\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f55", "question": "What James Joyce story collection begins with \"The Sisters\" and ends with \"The Dead\"?", "answer": "Dubliners", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a1e1e78b5a031299b745740", "question": "What year did Great Britain claim the eastern half of Australia?", "answer": "1770", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe938326bd93ce3a4e5f67f", "question": "Hydrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a066", "question": "What was the name of John Lennon and Cynthia Lennon's son?", "answer": "Julian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf26", "question": "What is the flower that stands for avarice?", "answer": "Scarlet auricula", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c074", "question": "What is the regulation height for a pin in Ten Pin bowling?", "answer": "Fifteen inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339628", "question": "What Canadian singer appeared on the first cover of \"Entertainment Weekly\"?", "answer": "K.D. Lang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ec", "question": "Which four states touch at one point?", "answer": "Utah, Colorado, Arizona, and New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce6", "question": "What Victor Hugo title character was enamored with a poor gypsy girl named Esmerelda?", "answer": "Quasimodo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7e", "question": "In 2006, what quarterback became the last USFL veteran to play in an NFL game?", "answer": "Doug Flutie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339840", "question": "In \"Monty Python And The Holy Grail\", what group demanded that Arthur bring them a shrubbery?", "answer": "The Knights who say Ni", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be8", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Anthony Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af82", "question": "Who died three months into his 4th term as president?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce1", "question": "What fashion brand was co-founded by Jay-Z and Damon Dash?", "answer": "Rocawear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3af", "question": "Which world champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?\u00a0", "answer": "Gary Kasparov", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33e", "question": "Archbishop Makarios of Cyprus was exiled in 1956 to where?", "answer": "The Seychelles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5f", "question": "What coastal Atlantic US state has \"The Shag\" as their official state dance?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887d", "question": "Who was King Lear's favorite daughter?", "answer": "Cordelia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906a", "question": "Which American poet also practiced medicine?", "answer": "Oliver Wendell Holmes Sr.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f42", "question": "Who created the character of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "William Hanna and Joseph Barbera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c860", "question": "What animal is also called a wildebeest?", "answer": "Gnu", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ec", "question": "What year did Guns N' Roses release the album \"The Spaghetti Incident\"?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eace4f83302ff91e46474", "question": "In which sport might you see a \"Crucifix\" being performed?", "answer": "Gynmastics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaca", "question": "On the banks of which river is the Taj Mahal?", "answer": "Yamuna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c7", "question": "The resort city of Aspen is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3d08ff048f679a45ab46", "question": "Tercel is the name for the male of which animal?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969a", "question": "The 1975 movie \"The Man Who Would Be King\" is based on the tales of which author?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76ff8eec85e375820b2f1", "question": "In which city was the 2000 movie \"Gladiator\" filmed?", "answer": "Ouarzazate", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad9", "question": "What Grand Slam sports event is held at Flushing Meadows, NY?", "answer": "US Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc0ec948005ec986edce1", "question": "Who is the eighth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Choerry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c65bfbde8045e48466b6", "question": "What liquid is known as the \"universal solvent\".", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caff", "question": "The drug quinine was originally isolated from the bark of which tree?", "answer": "Cinchona", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d4", "question": "What does a phonophobe fear?", "answer": "Noise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b2bb01dd7bf43be5e7a2", "question": "A group of ferrets is called what?", "answer": "A business", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9a", "question": "What fast food chain was founded by Glen Bell in 1962?", "answer": "Taco Bell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600399f257a0e35c43f838a1", "question": "Which artist was a fashion editor and a painter in the school of magic realism?", "answer": "Tichenor\u00a0-- She considered her work to be of a spiritual nature, reflecting ancient occult religions and Mesoamerican mythology.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb1", "question": "Who installed the first Archbishop of Canterbury in 597 AD?", "answer": "Pope Gregory l", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac52", "question": "What was the first animal sent up to outer space?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c32", "question": "How many seasons did the TV show \"Twin Peaks\" run for?", "answer": "2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef96e56ce05a3942286ea3", "question": "In the first televised baseball game, the Cincinnati Reds played what team?", "answer": "Brooklyn Dodgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339585", "question": "Which rock star was \"The Man Who Fell on Earth\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5f", "question": "Who played in his twenty-third and final NHL All-Star Game as a Hartford Whaler?", "answer": "Gordie Howe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59e", "question": "What pigment makes plants green?", "answer": "Chlorophyll", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f21", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Gailard Sartain and Stephen Lee?", "answer": "The Big Bopper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd4b5d00d154d7af00b8cd", "question": "Who released the song \"Gettin' Jiggy With It\"?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b2", "question": "What color flag is the signal for surrender?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c825", "question": "What common aquarium fish is named for the naturalist who discovered it in Trinidad in 1876?", "answer": "The guppy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e75", "question": "What superteam includes Robin, Kid Flash, Aqualad and Wonder Girl?", "answer": "The Teen Titans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991c", "question": "Who occupied the center square on the game show \u201cThe Hollywood Squares\u201d from 1998\u00ad to 2002?", "answer": "Whoopi Goldberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339197", "question": "What is the name of the White Stripes' drummer?", "answer": "Meg White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4b", "question": "What popular architect design The Louvre's distinctive glass pyramid in its central courtyard?", "answer": "I.M. Pei", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f6", "question": "What units are ship speeds measured in?", "answer": "Knots", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cc", "question": "A free radical is an atom or molecule that has an odd number of what?", "answer": "Electrons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c3", "question": "What kinds of creatures were Flopsy and Mopsy in the first book by Beatrix Potter?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c347b815febcc896f9252", "question": "Over which distance did Steve Ovett win Olympic gold?", "answer": "800 meters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d6", "question": "What two ingredients are used to make the standard Stinger cocktail?", "answer": "Cognac and white creme de menthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fb", "question": "How many US state names begin with \"New\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca00", "question": "What is the technical term for an organism that eats other organisms as food?", "answer": "A heterotroph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ecae4a7790ded87bb38fd8c", "question": "Who was the leading goalscorer for SKC in 2012?", "answer": "Kei Kamara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d0e1bb53d1af658864fe", "question": "The \"Christmas Price Index\" tracks the cost of what items?", "answer": "The gifts in the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7b", "question": "In the 1890's, what type of cheese did a California man named David Jacks introduce?", "answer": "Monterey Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a311", "question": "Which 1970's sci-fi film featured a space ship named \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afac", "question": "What was Sunday, January 30th 1972, generally remembered as in Ireland?", "answer": "Bloody Sunday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83a", "question": "What food got its name by the way it hung in bunches like grapes?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f700ea9e54d890926f6d4", "question": "South America\u2019s Atacama Desert holds what distinction?", "answer": "Driest non-polar desert -- Although it is home to about one million people, it records less than 1 mm of rain every year.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef1", "question": "What 1968 hit was the first song to use the phrase \"heavy metal\"?", "answer": "Born to Be Wild", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a889", "question": "What two US state capitals are named for people who were executed?", "answer": "Raleigh and St. Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d9", "question": "What colour is the Ring of Death that signifies that your Xbox 360 is broken forever?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa55b3c73aa70ea0b70b25", "question": "Which Central American country has a name which translates to English as \"The Saviour\"?", "answer": "El Salvador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b55c", "question": "Depending on the story, which two fruits are often considered the Queen of Fruits?", "answer": "Mangos and Mangosteens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cc", "question": "What cards do you have if you have a \"Big Slick\" in the game \"Texas Hold 'Em\"?", "answer": "An ace and a king of the same suit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937eb8808d98002fdd633af", "question": "In which city would you find Red Square?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed0", "question": "What game of chance was originally called \"Beano\"?", "answer": "Bingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c687", "question": "What is the average lifespan of the hummingbird?", "answer": "5 years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65b", "question": "The city of St. Louis is located in which state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af33", "question": "What year did Adolf Hitler rise to power in Germany?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c50efbde8045e48466a6", "question": "What is a phanerogam?", "answer": "Plants that produce seeds -- The most advanced plants on the evolutionary scale, they used to go by the name spermatophytes.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fe", "question": "What year was Jesus Christ (Jesus of Nazareth) born in?", "answer": "7 - 2 BC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f83", "question": "Who is associated with the address 221B Baker Street, London?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93c", "question": "How many flat faces does a dodecahedron have?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b434", "question": "How long did the Mau Mau Uprising last?", "answer": "8 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c1", "question": "Who is the world's richest duck?", "answer": "Scrooge McDuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f53", "question": "Who is Dinah, whom Alice thinks about nostalgically as she falls down the rabbit hole to Wonderland?", "answer": "Her cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c6e40775fa611bce67d4", "question": "A legislature that has legislators in two separate assemblies, chambers, or houses is called what?", "answer": "Bicameral", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74e", "question": "What plant is the most common cause of hay fever?", "answer": "Ragweed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a831", "question": "The powerful Inca empire had its capital seat at Cuzco in what modern-day South American country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25b", "question": "Which English county was Alfred Hitchcock born in?", "answer": "Essex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8a", "question": "In a nursery rhyme, whose wife \"Could eat no lean\"?", "answer": "Jack Sprat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30d", "question": "What flowers are known as \"mums\"?", "answer": "Chrysanthemums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce5", "question": "What is Mr. Belvedere's given name?", "answer": "Lynn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be59", "question": "What kind of animal is Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "A mouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff668a652a821ff76ae8b07", "question": "How many electors make up the Electoral College in the U.S.?", "answer": "538", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d1", "question": "What sport was played by the Brooklyn Dodgers?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3a", "question": "Which basketball superstar had a major role in the 1996 movie \"Space Jam\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf8", "question": "What does POTUS stand for?", "answer": "President of the United States", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9e", "question": "In the nursery rhyme \"Ladybird, Ladybird\", why is the bug told to \"fly away home\"?", "answer": "Her house is on fire and her children are gone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a144", "question": "Who is Scooby Doo's nephew??", "answer": "Scrappy Doo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b571", "question": "Who scored the \"Hand of God\" goal?", "answer": "Diego Maradona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339796", "question": "Fond of flesh and fava beans, what bad guy was named the American film institutes top villain of all time?", "answer": "Hannibal Lecter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4c", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Naked Kiss\"?", "answer": "Constance Towers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abf", "question": "\"The Imperial March\" is the theme music of what movie villain?", "answer": "Darth Vader", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd201ec223966ae8f88c2", "question": "How many visible cuts are there in the 2014 film \"Birdman\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c6c4877e98cb977789bf", "question": "What country has a national park called the \"Valley of Flowers\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad5", "question": "What first name is the Russian equivalent of John?", "answer": "Ivan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca91", "question": "What is a \"kiwano\" a type of?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae96", "question": "The 16th Constitutional Amendment, enacted in 1913 allowed the US federal government to do what?", "answer": "Tax personal income", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f40e01dd7bf43be5e81d", "question": "DIY stands for what?", "answer": "Do It Yourself", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd4", "question": "Whose \"Play-Along\" included fellow socks Charley Horse and Hush Puppy?", "answer": "Lamb Chop's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2bc", "question": "What year did the TV show \"30 Rock\" end its 7 year run?", "answer": "2013", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b2", "question": "Which actress, famous for her fruit hats, was the inspiration for the Chiquita banana logo?", "answer": "Carmen Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d48", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Dragonfly\"?", "answer": "Alison Lohman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29a", "question": "What planet has the shortest year?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b7f6364247bf200fb879", "question": "Which Russian chemist created the modern periodic table?", "answer": "Dmitri Mendeleev", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecf", "question": "Whose last book was \"Oh, the Places You'll Go\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a30", "question": "What athlete's late-night talk show was cancelled after only 8 weeks, in 1998?", "answer": "Magic Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ecaea45790ded87bb38fd8e", "question": "When measured from its underwater base, what is the tallest mountain?", "answer": "Mauna Kea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f749ea9e54d890926f6fb", "question": "Georgia, it\u2019s illegal to eat what with a fork?", "answer": "Fried chicken", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a173", "question": "Who created the characters Wallace and Gromit?", "answer": "Nick Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d185823b17032616b590ff", "question": "When was Nescafe's instant coffee first launched?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989aee8cb8751d53e7d7618", "question": "What is the largest North American country by land area?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae9420574a5ce6b56b8243", "question": "What US state is \"The Gopher State\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a80", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a temperature of how many degrees?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe698a120565ad31a57c736", "question": "Who was Telemachus?", "answer": "Odysseus' son", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75a", "question": "What is the name of the baby depicted on the Sacagawea dollar coin?", "answer": "Pomp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd8cb6ce05a3942286d74", "question": "Which NBA player has had a tattoo of the late Malcolm X on his left calf at least since 2012?", "answer": "Derrick Rose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe52b781bf59ab7d2e38103", "question": "What French word does \"collage\" come from?", "answer": "To glue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f916fa5fdd6dd25324f4", "question": "Dendrochronology is better known as what?", "answer": "Ring dating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7fe", "question": "Which planet was originally known as the Georgian Star?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b9bd364247bf200fb890", "question": "What kind of bones once stiffened corsets?", "answer": "Whale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad05", "question": "Where were the 1996 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Atlanta, Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd3", "question": "What 3 word phrase is written on Martin Luther King's gravestone?", "answer": "Free At Last", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b024", "question": "What decisive battle of the Civil War culminated on July 4, 1863 in Mississippi?", "answer": "Battle of Vicksburg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571bd067df192a942e336d", "question": "In the book \"Animal Farm\", what is the name of the farm?", "answer": "Manor Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339794", "question": "In which US state did the Charleston originate?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa7c20565ad31a57c819", "question": "Who is last in succession for president of the U.S.?", "answer": "Secretary of Homeland Security", "category": "history"}]